# **LUCHAO QI**

Baltimore, MD https://www.linkedin.com/in/LuchaoQi/

lqi9@jhu.edu | (443)-839-9129 https://luchaoqi.com/

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Technically-sophisticated top performer with comprehensive experience in performing quantitative analysis and data management for analytics studies utilizing state-of-the-art technologies to collect, clean, analyze, predict, and effectively communicate information. Possess an in-depth understanding of machine learning algorithms and advanced statistics such as regression, time-series forecasting, clustering, decision trees, exploratory data analysis methodology, simulation, scenario analysis, modeling, optimization, unstructured data analysis, and neural networks.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

**Programming:** Python, R (Shiny), SQL, Bash (Linux) **Visualization**: Tableau, Matplotlib, Seaborn, ggplot2, plotly

Packages & Frameworks: NumPy, Pandas, NLTK, scikit-learn, PyTorch, TensorFlow (Keras), Hadoop

Machine Learning& Deep Learning: GLM, Random Forest, SVM, PCA, CNN, RNN, Reinforcement Learning

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### The Johns Hopkins Data Science Lab, Baltimore, MD

08/2019-04/2020

Research Data Scientist

- Demonstrated mastery in spearheading project focused on association analysis between lifestyle patterns and body mass index (BMI)
- Processed data from the National Health & Nutrition Examination Survey by using dplyr and tidyverse
- Drastically decreased data dimensionality through facilitating principal component analysis (PCA) and also predicted user BMI with 46.07 mean squared error by training a generalized linear model (GLM)
- Achieved a 13% error reduction rate utilizing nested ANOVA (F-test) on principal component groupings
- Recognized for expertise in identifying vital (p-value < 0.5) associations between BMI, age, race, and physical activity level to encourage multiple healthy behaviors

## Johns Hopkins University, Bloomberg School of Public Health, Baltimore, MD

04/2019 - 07/2019

- Data Analyst Intern
  - Executed and managed research project on survival analysis of accelerometer time-series data and also optimized data value through researching on user distribution on Hadoop with MapReduce
  - Employed the use of Keras to predict mortality with 71% accuracy and structured a spectral-based convolutional neural network (CNN) on subjects
  - Accomplished in implementing regularized logistic regression for achieving an 86.45% increase rate in mortality prediction accuracy
  - Piloted the process of using ggplot2 and plotly for hosting R Shiny website comparing machine learning algorithms (PCA, k-means, UMAP, and t-SNE) & visualized clustering results

### Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Shenzhen, China

11/2016 - 05/2017

Data Analyst Intern

- Utilized spectral analysis for the project on EMG signal pattern recognition for hand gestures
- Pioneered the process of using Fast Fourier Transform for denoising time-domain signals of 200 gestures
- Generated an 82% accuracy rate in using support vector machines (SVM) for classifying hand movements
- Delivered extensive and innovative insights for medical rehabilitation systems while increasing the neural network training accuracy by 3%

#### **EDUCATION**

## Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD

05/2020

Master of Science in Engineering Degree -- Biomedical Data Science (GPA: 3.65/4.0)

Northeastern University, Liaoning, China

05/2018

Bachelor of Science Degree -- Biomedical Engineering (GPA: 3.85/4.0)